# **Gabriel Dias Machado**

### gabriel.d.machado92@gmail.com

+55 41 99610-7644 https://github.com/gabrieldmac/

#### **PROFILE**

I've been working as a Solutions Engineer for over 4 years now, but I want to move back to software development, I've been building a portfolio but I'm also searching for a position to help me get back to coding.

My experience as a Solutions engineer helps me a lot in improving my communication and understanding of the business needs of my clients, also I have contact with multiple types of platforms when I'm helping my customers integrate with the platform I'm supporting.

### Please check my personal website for sample projects

#### **SKILLS**

- Full Stack Web Development
- ReactJS
- Python
- Flask
- Docker
- API
- MaterialUI
- VueJS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Metamap, Brazil—Solutions Engineer

Jan 2021 - now

I'm responsible to make sure that every merchant (client) that has signed a contract (or is about to) with Mati has the best experience with our product, from the signup, free trial, until using the Mati dashboard and integrating our SDKs or APIs.

### EBANX, Brazil—Sales Engineer

26 Sep 2018 - Jan 2021

I'm responsible to help merchants go live with EBANX payment services by providing guidance through our APIs and different integration methods that fit any type of merchant business model and sizes, coordinating the integration of merchants into the EBANX payments processing platform (APIs connectivity or E-commerce plugin extensions), by configuring front and back-office systems to ensure merchants have access to our products and services.

## ExxonMobil, Brazil— System Analyst

Aug 2016 - Jul 2018

Making the life of our business easier was my main concern, talking with them, learning their pain points, and, after that, automating the process were my day-to-day activities. Other than that, I was always concerned about the best way my team could work to better attend to our business, upgrade our agile methodologies with Kanban, and stand-up daily meetings.

### **TIVIT**, Brazil — Software Developer

Apr2014 - Oct 2015

Worked on Java-based projects side by side with the architect learning how to build the best software in the best way there is

#### **EDUCATION**

## MBA, Commercial Management — FGV(Fundação Getúlio Vargas)

Jun 2020 - Nov 2022

### **Computer System Analysis** — *Positivo University*

Jan 2017 - Dec 2019

#### **EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

Co-Founder of a crowdfunding platform for teachers from public schools from Brazil, to help them fund projects like buying books for their schools, building a science lab or materials for the sports court.

#### **LANGUAGES**

English - Advanced

Portuguese - Native